In all of the previous lessons,
we've been using these boxes to represent a code editor where
we wrote our Python code and output window where we viewed results.
And in the classroom,
you use these programming quizzes to write Python and run
your code but instead of running your code online in the classroom,
you can run Python on your own computer by installing
Python and useful tools for your programming environment.
Since Python is a popular open-source programming language,
it's free to download,
change and use and the fact that it's already popular means
there are online instructions to help you get it
installed for most common operating systems.
Because it's popular and open-source,
there's a large global community working on developing Python.
For you, as a Python user,
that means there'll be new versions coming out as Python is improved by the community.
You might find yourself needing to update Python from time to time especially if you're
collaborating with other people as you write
Python programs that are compatible with the version they're using.
Now, it's time for you to install Python.