Now that you've successfully installed Python,
let's try to run a script in your terminal.
First, download the file first_script.py
attached at the bottom of this page and move it to an appropriate directory.
I put my file here by dragging it from the downloads folder to this folder.
This might be a good time to set up
a new directory for your learning if you don't have one already.
Next, open your terminal and use CD
to navigate to the directory containing the downloaded file.
I can double check that the file is located here by typing ls or dir on Windows.
Now that you're in the directory with the file,
you can run it by typing python followed by
the name of the file like this. Then press enter.
You'll know you've run the scripts successfully if you see this message.
Whenever you type Python followed by the file name for a Python script,
that script is run and the output is shown immediately afterwards.
Once the codes finished running,
and all the output has been shown,
your command line prompt reappears.
Note if you typed and entered just Python without a script to run,
it'll start an interactive interpreter for Python.
You'll learn more about this later.
For now, you can just type in exit with parentheses to get out or alternatively,
control D on Mac and Linux or control Z and enter on Windows.
Now, I'm back to the command line prompt.
It's your turn. Download the file below and run the script in your terminal.